大家好 欢迎来到EnjoyZ评测组球鞋简介
Hello.Welcome to EnjoyZ Review
我是小唐
I'm MR.Tang
出现在屏幕上的这双Morelia Neo
Here comes the Morelia Neo
作为美津浓Morelia的速度型分支
As the speed category of Mizuno
超轻量袋鼠皮球鞋这个称呼
So called 'Superlight Kangaroo'
显然瞬间吸引了无数目光
Appealing to lots of interests
它最早在2011年末上市
Having been released at the later of 2011
可是后来因为鞋钉设计上的缺陷
But according to the defect of studs design
导致它在人草上频频出现断钉事件
Leading to the frequency studs broken on AG
于是美津浓痛定思痛
Hence Mizuno recalls the lessons
在今年年初推出了改进版的二代鞋钉 就是它了
Revealed the redisigned second generation of studs
美津浓官方也自信的在官方网站声明它人草适用
Confidently,Mizuco declaimed that it should be well suited on AG
但评测组的建议呢是它适合质量中上乘的人草
But in our opinion,we suggest you wearing it on smug and superior AG
垃圾人草还是不行
Muddy AG?Damn it
这个天蓝配色在刚刚曝光的时候
Since the early glimpse of this fresh blue colorway
曾获得评测组的成员一致的赞叹
We feld all in love with it
因为图片上的蓝色实在是太漂亮了
The fresh blue is so brilliant
但是拿到实物之后我们发现
But now that we get the real shoes
其实这个蓝色并没有宣传图上那么地鲜艳
The blue is not as shining as the images posed
而且不是很耐脏
Besides the shoes would be caught mud easily
不过那么漂亮的颜色 管他呢
But,it could be forgiven
既然是速度型战靴
As speed boots
那么重量就是很致命的环节
The weight is the whole we really concerned about
以JP 255的尺码为例 重量是165克
Take a look at the JP 255(EU 40),the weight is 165g
显然入选世界最轻足球鞋排行榜前十
Must be the Top 10 of lightest Soccer boots
可以说是毫无压力
Undoubtedly
在说鞋形之前先谈谈Morelia Neo的两个产地
We should talk about the two places of production first.
一处是老家日本
The one is the basis of Mizuno,Japan
另一处则是东南亚的印尼
The other is southeastern Indonesia
我们都知道美津浓的鞋子
As we know
日产有分别专供本国的版本
Mizuno "Made in Japan" includes two versions
和供应国际市场的国际版两种
One for the inland and one for the interational market
就拿这双来说
Take these shoes
它的日产和印尼产均为国际版
The JP outputs and ID outputs are all international version
从鞋形上和专供日本市场的Estrela Neo一对比就可以看出
We can destinguish it from the JP only Estrela Neo on the outline
为了适应欧洲人的脚型
In order to adjust to the European size of foots
Morelia Neo的国际版显然比专供日本市场的Estrela Neo要窄
International Morelia Neo is thinner than the JP only version at the forefoot
但稍微比一般的欧美系品牌略宽一些
But a bit wider than the common Western brands
如果穿Estrela Neo正好的朋友在选购这双鞋的时候要注意了
Anyone who fits Estrela Neo well should be cautious while consider buying these
这双鞋秉承了美津浓的一贯作风
These shoes are typical Mizuno
特别是这个有收紧设计的鞋口
Especially for the tight designed shoe throat
我们在Estrela Neo的简介视频中有提到过
We have referred it in the review of Estrela Neo
制作这种鞋口需要制鞋工艺精湛的鞋匠才能完成
This kind of shoe throat must be completed by the top level artists
由此可见 美津浓确实是很认真地在对待他们出品的每一双球鞋
Mizuno is very into every shoes they made indeed
无论产地在哪里
No matter where it could be produced
Morelia Neo的鞋面采用的是前段袋鼠皮和后段人造材料的设计
Morelia Neo is combined by Kangaroo at the front and the rest of synthetical leather
前段的袋鼠皮从按压的感觉来看
According to the pressing feel of the forefoot
和我们之前测试的Estrela Neo一样并不是很柔软
It is not very soft same as the reviewed Estrela Neo
这种选材显然是为了平衡触感和发力
This construct should be made to balance the touch and converting power
按压时还可以感觉到Morelia Neo的袋鼠皮
You can feel it while pressing the forefoot
比Estrela Neo要厚一些
The forefoot material is thicker than Estrela Neo
这个对触感的影响其实并不大
That should be hard to effect on the touch
按照个人喜好判断即可
Take one as you like
后段的人造材料和Estrela Neo一样
The synthetic material is the same as Estrala Neo
这种设计的好处就是鞋口不容易变形 松垮
That kind of design assures the shoe throat should hardly be twisted or loosened
保持脚外侧支撑的同时
While keeping the outstep support
能够让球鞋更加包脚
It makes the shoes fit your feet better
所以大家再别迷信全袋鼠皮的鞋子了
So do not keep your stubborn in the Kangaroo boots
除非它在这个位置提供了内衬补强
Unless it could offer the same support with interlining
在这里要跟大家说明一下
We should emphasize here that
日产和印尼产的Morelia Neo使用的袋鼠皮
The Kangaroo used in JP and ID version Morelia Neo
触感上是同等质量的
Expressing same level of touch
不过日产会对皮面进行抛光处理
But the outside of JP version has special polishing treatment
所以看起来更加高端一些
So on glance it could be seen as high-end
而且日产的价格比印尼产贵了不少
Besides that the JP output is much more expensive than IN output
以这双为例
Take a look at these
淘宝日产的价格1400元左右
The JP output would cost you RMB 1400 on taobao.com
而且还没有天蓝色可以选择
In addition,you can not get a fresh blue one
印尼的呢才九百多
But the IN output is just a little less than RMB 1000
性价比来看
Considering the cost performance
印尼显然更有优势
Maybe IN output is better
Morelia Neo的大底使用了轻量化球鞋的标配
The soleplate of Morelia Neo inports the common design of Mizuno light boots
尼龙与TPU复合
Combined with nylon and TPU
大底大面积采用尼龙
The soleplate is mainly made from nylon
而鞋钉为了增加耐磨性和硬度则选用了TPU
While the studs are made from TPU for better fricktion tolerance and hardness
说到鞋钉 我们之前已经说过是使用了改进后的新一代设计
We have said that the studs have been redesigned
所以官方宣称可以在中等以上的人草使用
So that Mizuno declaims that it could well fits the beyond average quality AG
但是具体会不会断钉还有视个人踢球习惯而定
But,whether the studs could be broken agains remain to be judged by your style
所以各位也要考虑自身的膝盖安全
So,watch out for your knees
体重太大的我劝你还是放弃吧
For the fatass,screw it
不得不说 对于美津浓来说
In my opinion,speak about Mizuno
日本产与印尼产的差距之小令人佩服
The differences between JP out and IN output could be ignored,maybe
但仍然有一定的差距
But the gap is still there
鞋身有多处溢胶以以及线头
We have found lots of overflow and ripped thread
但是需要声明的是
But we could declare that
溢胶其实恰恰证明了胶水的量足但看起来不美观
The overflow proves Mizuno did not fake their work
很讽刺吧 今后我们会在EnjoyZ Lab中给大家普及
What a sarcasm,maybe we will talk about that in EnjoyZ Lab
既然它是轻量化球鞋
As light speed boots
那么可以减轻球鞋重量的半中底设计便是必不可少的了
The design of cutting half midfoot to reduce weigh is essential
至于加强梁的硬度我们在Estrela Neo的视频中有具体说明
As for the strengthen beam,we have specific reviewed it in Estrela Neo
这里就不作赘述了
Chaka Chaka
后跟和鞋口采用了防滑的麂皮材料
The heel and throat are made from skid-resistant suede
这可以让球鞋更加跟脚
That assures the shoes fit well
不过鞋垫依然是普通的发泡材料
But the insole pad is still polyurethane foam
让人很是无语啊
Suck it
再来看看鞋带
Then we take a look at the laces
前细后粗的鞋带已经成为市场主流
Slim front and wide end laces are the common choice nowadays
但美津浓依然没有在鞋带上面做出什么改进
So that Mizuno improves no more than that
所以如果有意入手的朋友担心鞋带会松动的话
If you consern about the loosen laces
我们还是推荐你换上EnjoyZ  Lab自主研发的
I suggest you buying a pair of EnjoyZ Lab homemade
Control+魔控鞋带
VEZi Control+ laces
那叫一个好评如潮哇
That is amazing one
总结一下
In conclusion
虽然Morelia Neo的印尼产离日产在做工上还有一定差距
Although ID output Morelia NEO could not match the JP output in making
但是这差距仅仅在少数细节上
But the differences are ignorable,just some details
并不影响实战中的表现
That would not make much defference in court
价格上与日产便宜得不是一点半点
The ID output Neo is far more cheap
如果合适的话
Appropriately
这款球鞋我们推荐入手
We would recommend it
好了 关于这款球鞋的介绍就是这么多了
So,that is all about the Morelia Neo
这里是EnjoyZ.com
Here we comes from EnjoyZ.com
EZ 改变你的足球生活
EZ Changing your soccer life
我是小唐 我们下期再见
My name is MR.Tang,see you next eposite